# Akansh Goel, (Front End Developer)

+91-9818902567, akansh111@gmail.com

LINKS	<u>LinkedIn</u> , <u>GitHub</u> , <u>HackerRank</u>	
PROFILE	Results-oriented Front End Developer with 6.5 years of experience developing responsive web applications. Well-versed in promoting object-oriented approaches to real-time software solutions. Easily communicates complex technical requirements to non-technical stakeholders. Have experience in leading development teams in enterprise-wide development projects.	
SKILLS	React JS	Material UI
	Redux-Saga	Ag-Grid
	JavaScript	Object Oriented Programming
	Typescript	CI/CD
	HTML5	Agile Methodologies
	CSS3	Jest & Enzyme
	ES6, ES7, ES8, ES9	Jira, Bitbucket, Confluence
	Bootstrap	Sonar

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Oct 2019 — Present

# Senior Associate Technology, PUBLICIS SAPIENT

Gurgaon

- Working on a platform for Wellington Portfolio Managers which enables them to access the dashboards and other investment-related data into the desktop-based openFin application.
- Collaborated with domain experts to understand and characterize products and identify problematic issues.
- Developing and implementing user interface components using React concepts.
- Troubleshooting interface software and debugging application codes.
- Monitoring and improving front-end performance.
- Introduced agile methodologies and development best practices to division to enhance product development.
- Trained and mentored junior developers and engineers, teaching skills in React Js and working to improve overall team performance.

Sep 2018 — Oct 2019

# Senior Software Engineer, MAGIC SOFTWARES PVT. LTD

Noida

- Worked on 'CYPRESS' engineering project which is e-learning CMS for PEARSON client.
- Orchestrated efficient large-scale software deployments.
- Gathered and defined customer requirements to develop clear specifications for project plans.
- Result-driven developer with experience in development universe and maintenance of complex systems/products.
- Worked on Higher Order Components to extend the functionality and to wrap it with other components.
- Revised, modularized and updated old code bases to modern development standards, reducing operating
  costs and improving functionality.

Jul 2015 — Sep 2018

# System Engineer, TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES

Noida

- Connected the React App to Redux store for state management.
- Worked on Higher-Order Components to extend the functionality and to wrap it with other components.
- · Assure that all user input is validated before submitting to the back-end.
- $\bullet \;\;$  Integrated with D3 charting library to implement various charts.
- Implemented firewalls, two-factor authentication, and antivirus software to maintain network integrity.

**EDUCATION** 

Aug 2011 — Jun 2015